Natalie Babbitt Papers 1994.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Natalie Babbitt Papers
undated, 1906-1991
1994.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
50.2 Linear feet
The papers of children's author and illustrator, Natalie Babbitt include correspondence, reviews, publicity, manuscripts, drafts, illustrations and finished artwork for sixteen books and several articles.
Babbitt, Natalie
Biography
Natalie Babbitt was born 28 July 1932, in Dayton, OH, the daughter of Ralph Zane and Genevieve (Converse) Moore. She received her B.A. from Smith College in 1954. That same year she married Samuel Fisher Babbitt, who also collaborated with her on her first book, The 49th Magician. Ms. Babbitt is a member of the Authors Guild, Authors League of America, and PEN (American Center).
Ms. Babbitt has received the Children's Literature Festival Award, Keene State College, for the body of her work (1993) as well as the following for individual titles:
The Search for Delicious--Best Book for Children Ages Nine to Twelve citation, New York Times (1969).
Kneeknock Rise--American Library Association (ALA) Notable Book citation (1970) Newbery Honor Book citation (1971) and Horn Book Honor citation.
Goody Hall--Book World Children's Spring Book Festival Honor Book citation (1971), Children's Book Council Showcase title (1972), and School Library Journal Honor List citation.
The Devil's Storybook--ALA Notable Book citation (1974), School Library Journal Best Book of the Year citation (1974), Horn Book Honor List citation (1974), and National Book Award nomination (1974).
Tuck Everlasting--ALA Notable Book citation (1976), Horn Book Honor List citation (1976), Christopher Award for juvenile fiction (1976), International Reading Association choices list citation (1978), U.S. Honor Book citation (1978), and Congress of the International Board on Books for Young People citation (1978).
The Eyes of the Amaryllis--ALA Notable Book citation (1977).
Herbert Rowbarge--George C. Stone Center for Children's Books award (1979), Hans Christian Andersen Medal nomination (1981), Best Books citation, New York Times (1982).
Ouch!--Blue Ribbon Book, Bulletin of the Center for Children's Books (1998), ALA Notable Book citation (1999), and Audie Award (2001).
General note
Published Works:
Samuel Fisher Babbitt, The Forty-ninth Magician, Pantheon, 1966. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, Dick Foote and the Shark, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1967. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, Phoebe's Revolt, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1968. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, The Search for Delicious, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1969. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, Kneeknock Rise, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1970. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, The Something, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1970. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, Goody Hall, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1971. Dodd CLC B463
Valerie Worth, Small Poems, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1972. Dodd CLC B496
Natalie Babbitt, The Devil's Story Book, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1974. Dodd CLC B229
Natalie Babbitt, Tuck Everlasting, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1975. Dodd CLC
Valerie Worth, More Small Poems, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1976. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, The Eyes of the Amaryllis, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1977. Dodd CLC B484
Valerie Worth, Still More Small Poems, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1978. Dodd CLC
Valerie Worth, Curlicues: The Fortunes of Two Pug Dogs, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1980 [published as Imp and Biscuit: The Fortunes of Two Pugs, London, England: Chatto & Windus, 1981 ]. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, Herbert Rowbarge, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1982. Dodd CLC B493
Valerie Worth, Small Poems Again, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1985. Dodd CLC
Valerie Worth, Other Small Poems Again, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1986. Dodd CLC
Valerie Worth, All the Small Poems, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1987. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, The Devil's Other Storybook, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1987. Dodd CLC B494
Natalie Babbitt, Nellie: A Cat on Her Own, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1989. Dodd CLC
Valerie Worth, All the Small Poems and Fourteen More, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 1994. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, Bub; or, The Very Best Thing, HarperCollins, 1994. Dodd CLC
Babbitt, Natalie(Reteller), Ouch!: A Tale from Grimm,, illustrated by Fred Marcellino, Harper Collins, 1998. Dodd CLC
Natalie Babbitt, Elsie Times Eight Hyperion Books, 2001. Dodd CLC
Valerie Worth, Peacock and Other Poems, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 2002. Dodd CLC
Scope and Content
The Natalie Babbitt Papers include correspondence, reviews, publicity, manuscripts, and artwork concerning Ms. Babbitt and her career. The collection includes dummies, manuscripts, drafts, sketches, illustrations, galleys and proofs for sixteen published books, two unpublished stories and several short stories.
Arrangement
Series I: Published Books ( undated, 1906-1991 ) arranged in chronological order by date of first publication includes sketches, drafts, dummies, original art, proofs, manuscripts and correspondence.
Series II: Published Articles and Short Stories ( undated, 1971-1978 ) is arranged chronologically by publication date and includes some artwork with the manuscript materials for the stories.
Series III: Unpublished materials ( circa 1953, circa 1963 ) contains the manuscripts and artwork for two unpublished stories.
Series IV: Subject Files ( undated, 1953-1961 ) includes programs, publicity, correspondence and award information regarding Ms. Babbitt's work.
Series V: Artifacts ( undated ).
Separated Material
The photographs, books, textbooks, and periodicals have all been separated from the collection. The photographs are located in Box 28.
The following separated materials have been cataloged:
Books:
H. Thompson Fillmer. American book English. Dodd CLC C7240
Babbitt, Natalie. At the Edge of the World. Dodd CLC C3733
Huck, Charlotte S. Bright horizons: a collection. Dodd CLC A2369
Building Reading Skills Dodd CLC C6011
Sutherland, Zena. Children and books. Dodd CLC C3730
Children of the Alps. Dodd CLC A2184
Children's Books Mean Business. Dodd CLC C6010
The Children's Carol. Dodd CLC A2173
Children's Literature. Dodd C6585
The Children's Book Showcase. Dodd CLC C6013
Spyri, Johanna. The Children's Carol. Dodd Call No.
The Christopher Robin Birthday Book. Dodd CLC A2180
Matteoni, Louise. Daystreaming. Dodd CLC C3697
Spyri, Johanna. Dora. Dodd CLC A2186
Babbitt, Natalie. East of the Sun. Dodd CLC C3732
Chagnon, Peggy. Fights: Theme II: conflict: anthology 2. Dodd CLC C3729
Ruddell, Robert B. Free rein. Dodd CLC C3667
The Great Excluded Critical essays on Children's Literature Dodd Call No.
Green Salad Seasons. Dodd CLC C3697
Tudor, Tasha. Illustrated Mother Goose. Dodd CLC A2176
Innocence and Experience Essays and Conversations on Children's Literature. Dodd C6586
Gilkison, Grace. The King's Christmas Pudding. Dodd CLC A2174
Earl Schneider, editor. Know your pug. Dodd WSF 3
Language for Daily Use. Dodd C7238
Language Skills and use. Dodd C6849
Miller, Olive, ed. Little Pictures of Japan. Dodd C3665
Thurber, James. Many Moons. Dodd CLC C210
Spyri, Johanna. Mazle. Dodd CLC A2187
Hopkins, Lee Bennett. Monsters, Ghoulies and Creepy creatures. Dodd CLC C3668
Ruddell, Robert B. Moon magic. Dodd CLC C3731
Hopkins, Lee Bennett. More books by More people: Interviews with 65 authors of books for children. (inscribed to Natalie Babbitt from author) Dodd Call No.
Mother Goose's Rhymes and poems. Dodd CLC A2183
Price, Margaret Evans. Myths and Enchantment Tales. Dodd CLC C3541
Angel, Marie. New Bestiary. Dodd Call No.
Lipson, Eden Ross. The New York Times parent's guide to the best books for children. Dodd CLC C3734
Once upon a time: celebrating the Magic of Children's books in honor of the Twentieth Anniversary of Reading is fundamental. Dodd Call No.
Field, Rachel. People from Dickens. Dodd CLC C1070
Hoffman, Carolyn. The Princess finds a playmate. Dodd CLC A2172
Trelease, Jim. The Read aloud handbook. Dodd Call No.
Boots, Jack. Ready or not skills book. Dodd CLC C6012
Something about the Author. volume 6. Dodd Call No.
Stories from Shakespeare. (inscribed to Natalie Babbitt from 'Mother") Dodd CLC A2182
Daniels, Jack. Tales Told in Holland. Dodd C3516
Kirkpatrick, D. L., ed. Twentieth-century children's writers. Dodd Call No. C6545
Spyri, Johanna. Vinzi. (owned by Margery Titus, inscribed from her mother 1923). Dodd CLC A2185
Stetson, Judy. Wellfleet. A Pictorial History Dodd A9772
Clymer, Theodore. Windows and walls. Dodd CLC C3726
Field, Eugene. With Trumpet and Drum. Dodd CLC A2181
Varlejs, Jana. Young adult literature in the seventies: a selection of readings. Dodd CLC C3727
Periodicals:
The Bulletin of the Center for Children's Books. February 1989
Children's Digest. October 1967, March 1971, April 1975
Clinical Symposia. v. 26, #4, 1974
Cricket the magazine for Children. volume 1, #5 January 1974, volume 1, #6 February 1974, volume 1, #8, April 1974.
Compton's yearbook 1978.
Harper's. January 1977
The Horn Book Magazine. February 1972, March/April 1989
Journal of Reading. Volume 31 Number 1 October 1987
Language Arts. November / December 1977
Library Talk. March/April 1988
The Lion and the Unicorn, Fantasy and creativity in Children's literature. vol. 1 #2 fall 1977
The New Yorker. 28 December 1981
Okapi. 15-30 November 1974
Publishers Weekly. July 26, 1976 Volume 210 No 4
The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress. Volume 39, Number 2 Spring 1982
Redbook. December 1971
Review. July/August 1987
Saturday Review. November 9, 1968
Scholastic Sprint. Sept 16, 1983 Volume 9 No. 1, Spring November 1/15, 1985 Volume 11, No 4
School Library Journal. January 1971
Short Story International. Seedling series number 5. 1982
Something about the author v.5
Touchdown School magazine. 1986, 1990
Wintersetl. Spring, 1974
The Writer. June 1971
Highlights. November 1966
Jack Plank Tells Tales 1994-0001.cd1
Acquisition Information
The collection was deposited in several installments by Ms. Babbitt.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Babbitt, Natalie; Audio visual materials; Audiocassettes; Authors, American; Books.; Children's literature; Contracts; Correspondence; Financial Records; Fliers [printed matter]; Galley proofs; Illustrations (layout features).; Illustrators; Manuscripts (document genre); Northeast Children's Literature Collection.; Notes; Photocopies; Photographs; Publications; Sketches; Sound recordings; Twentieth century.; Typescripts; Videocassettes; Works of Art
- Series I: Published Books, undated, 1906-
  - 49th Magician, 1966
    - Dummy, undated (Box 24:, Folder 172)
    - Manuscript--Typescript and Galley, undated (Box 22:, Folder 154)
    - Original art, undated (Box 22:, Folder 155)
    - Cover original art, undated (Box 24:, Folder 173)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 22:, Folder 156)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1985 (Box 22:, Folder 157)
    - Reviews and publisher's catalogs, 1966 (Box 22:, Folder 158)
  - Dick Foote and the shark, 1967
    - Dummies, undated (Box 23:, Folder 159)
    - Manuscript--Typescript, undated (Box 23:, Folder 160)
    - Original art, undated (Box 23:, Folder 161)
    - Original art, undated (Box 24:, Folder 174)
    - Sketches, copies, text and overlays, undated (Box 23:, Folder 162)
    - Galleys and page proofs, undated (Box 23:, Folder 163)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 23:, Folder 164)
    - Proofs with binding sample, undated (Box 23:, Folder 165)
    - Folded and gathered (annotated), undated (Box 23:, Folder 166)
    - Cover proofs, undated (Box 23:, Folder 167)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1966-1975 (Box 23:, Folder 168)
    - Research, undated (Box 23:, Folder 169)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1967 (Box 23:, Folder 170)
    - Publisher's catalog, 1967-1968 (Box 23:, Folder 171)
  - Phoebe's revolt, 1968
    - Sketches - pencil illustrations of girls, women, babies, nurses, maids, dresses, men, hairstyles, hats, furniture, floor plans, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Dummies, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Research photocopies of newspaper articles on turn of the century homes, silver, dolls, undated, 1906, 1965-1966 (Box 2:, Folder 8)
    - Manuscript and dummy, undated (Box 2:, Folder 9)
    - Photographs for models, undated (Box 2:, Folder 10)
    - Original Art--used (In order of appearance in book), undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Original Art--not used (often similar to used illustrations, with subtle differences in perspective or facial expressions), undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 2:, Folder 11)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 2:, Folder 12)
    - Jacket design, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1978 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
    - Publicity (includes book mark ad, magazine booklists, two descriptions of 'sexism' of book), undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - The Search for Delicious, 1969
    - Original manuscript (photocopy), undated (Box 19:, Folder 117)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 19:, Folder 118)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 19:, Folder 119)
    - Original art, undated (Box 19:, Folder 120)
    - Galley, undated (Box 19:, Folder 122)
    - Galley, undated (Box 19:, Folder 122)
    - Printer's proof, undated (Box 19:, Folder 123)
    - Repros untouched, undated (Box 20:, Folder 124)
    - Page proofs, undated (Box 20:, Folder 125)
    - British edition line editing, undated (Box 20:, Folder 126)
    - Cover art and layout, undated (Box 20:, Folder 127)
    - Cover and interior map art, undated (Box 24:, Folder 175)
    - Cover proofs, undated (Box 20:, Folder 128)
    - Binding samples, undated (Box 20:, Folder 129)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1968-1981, 1989 (Box 20:, Folder 130)
    - Reviews, 1969-1971 (Box 20:, Folder 131)
    - Publicity, undated (Box 20:, Folder 132)
    - Publisher's cataloges, 1969-1975 (Box 20, Folder 133)
    - Curriculum integration Grade 4, 1981 (Box 20:, Folder 134)
    - Dramatization, undated (Box 20:, Folder 135)
    - Literature Curriculum unit, 1989 (Box 20:, Folder 136)
  - Kneeknock Rise, 1970
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4:, Folder 19)
    - Original art--used, undated (Box 3:, Folder 14)
    - Original art--not used, undated (Box 3:, Folder 15)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 4:, Folder 20)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 4:, Folder 21)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 4:, Folder 22)
    - Jacket design--used, undated (Box 3:, Folder 16)
    - Jacket design not used, undated (Box 3:, Folder 17)
    - Jacket proofs, undated (Box 3:, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1987 (Box 4:, Folder 23)
    - Publicity, undated, 1970-1987 (Box 4:, Folder 24)
  - The Something, 1970
    - Manuscript (mss and ts), undated (Box 5:, Folder 25)
    - Dummies, undated (Box 5:, Folder 26)
    - Original art--used, undated (Box 5:, Folder 27)
    - Original art--not used, undated (Box 5:, Folder 28)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 5:, Folder 29)
    - Jacket design--used, undated (Box 5:, Folder 30)
    - Jacket design--not used, undated (Box 5:, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1970-1982 (Box 5:, Folder 32)
    - Publicity and reviews, undated, 1970-1971, 1973, 1977 (Box 5:, Folder 33)
  - Goody Hall, 1971
    - Manuscript (first draft), undated (Box 6:, Folder 34)
    - Manuscript (ts), undated (Box 6:, Folder 35)
    - Manuscript (final draft), undated (Box 7:, Folder 41)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 6:, Folder 36)
    - Original art (hardcover and paperback)--used, undated (Box 7:, Folder 42)
    - Original art--not used, undated (Box 6:, Folder 37)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 7:, Folder 43)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 7:, Folder 44)
    - Jacket design (hardcover and paperback)--used, undated (Box 6:, Folder 38)
    - Jacket design--not used, undated (Box 6:, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1985 (Box 7:, Folder 45)
    - Publicity and reviews, undated, 1984 (Box 6:, Folder 40)
  - The Devil's Storybook, 1974
    - [Note: working title "The Brimstone Papers"]
    - Manuscript (ms and ts), undated (Box 8:, Folder 46)
    - Original art--used, undated (Box 8:, Folder 47)
    - Original art--not used, undated (Box 8:, Folder 48)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 8:, Folder 49)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 8:, Folder 50)
    - Jacket design (British version), undated (Box 8:, Folder 51)
    - Jacket proofs and design(American and British versions), undated (Box 8:, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1971-1986 (Box 8:, Folder 53)
  - Tuck Everlasting, 1975
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 9:, Folder 54)
    - Manuscript--TS, undated (Box 9:, Folder 55)
    - Manuscript--TS, undated (Box 9:, Folder 56)
    - Jacket design--used (Hardcover and paperback), undated (Box 9:, Folder 57)
    - Jacket art--used (Hardcover and paperback), undated (Box 9:, Folder 58)
    - Jacket art--not used, undated (Box 9:, Folder 59)
    - Jacket proofs, undated (Box 10:, Folder 60)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 10:, Folder 61)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 10:, Folder 62)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 10:, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 11:, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 11:, Folder 65)
    - Publicity, reviews, clippings, awards and articles, 1975-1976 (Box 11:, Folder 66)
    - Publicity, reviews, clippings, awards and articles, 1977-1983 (Box 11:, Folder 67)
    - Publicity, reviews, clippings, awards and articles, 1984-1991 (Box 11:, Folder 68)
  - Eyes of the Amaryllis, 1977
    - First draft and notes, undated (Box 12:, Folder 69)
    - Manuscript draft--Typescript, undated (Box 12:, Folder 70)
    - Final draft and editors notes, undated (Box 12:, Folder 71)
    - Manuscript--Typescript, undated (Box 12:, Folder 72)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 12:, Folder 73)
    - Printers Galleys, undated (Box 13:, Folder 74)
    - Folded and Gathered, undated (Box 13:, Folder 75)
    - Jacket proofs, undated (Box 13:, Folder 75)
    - Cover art, undated (Box 13:, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence, reviews and catalogs, 1977-1979 (Box 13:, Folder 77)
  - Still more small poems, 1978
    - Dummy (Box 25:, Folder 176)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 25:, Folder 177)
    - Jacket proof, undated (Box 25:, Folder 178)
    - Folded and gathered, undated (Box 25:, Folder 179)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 25:, Folder 180)
    - Reviews, 1979-1981 (Box 25:, Folder 181)
  - Curlicues, 1980
    - Dummy, undated (Box 14:, Folder 78)
    - Manuscript-- Valerie Worth, undated (Box 14:, Folder 79)
    - Original art, undated (Box 14:, Folder 80)
    - Original cover art, undated (Box 14:, Folder 81)
    - Typeset, undated (Box 14:, Folder 82)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 14:, Folder 83)
    - Photographs (separation sheets), undated (Box 14:, Folder 84)
  - Herbert Rowbarge, 1982
    - Manuscript, early draft, undated (Box 15:, Folder 85)
    - Manuscript, partial draft, undated (Box 15:, Folder 86)
    - Partial draft (ts) -- annotated, undated (Box 15:, Folder 87)
    - First draft, undated (Box 15:, Folder 88)
    - Draft -- typescript, undated (Box 15:, Folder 89)
    - Draft -- edited typescript, undated (Box 15:, Folder 90)
    - Manuscript--Bound typescript annotated, undated (Box 16:, Folder 91)
    - Galley, undated (Box 16:, Folder 92)
    - Galley, undated (Box 16:, Folder 93)
    - Galley, undated (Box 16:, Folder 94)
    - Cover art--not used, undated (Box 16:, Folder 95)
    - Cover art--not used, undated (Box 16:, Folder 95)
    - Jacket proofs, undated (Box 16:, Folder 97)
    - Folded and gathered with cover, undated (Box 16:, Folder 98)
    - Chronology, undated (Box 17:, Folder 99)
    - Map--IL, IN, OH, KY, undated (Box 17:, Folder 100)
    - Research and notes, undated (Box 17:, Folder 101)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1975-1985 (Box 17:, Folder 102)
    - Publicity, reviews and clippings, undated, 1982-1985 (Box 17:, Folder 103)
  - Devil's Other Storybook, 1986
    - Manuscript--Draft, undated (Box 18:, Folder 104)
    - Manuscript--TS stories, undated (Box 18:, Folder 105)
    - Manuscript--TS annotated, undated (Box 18:, Folder 106)
    - Original art, undated (Box 18:, Folder 107)
    - Master Galleys, 1986 (Box 18:, Folder 108)
    - Master pages, 1987 (Box 18:, Folder 109)
    - Galleys--Corrected, undated (Box 18:, Folder 110)
    - Proofs--Annotated, undated (Box 18:, Folder 111)
    - Folded and gathered, undated (Box 18:, Folder 112)
    - Cover art, undated (Box 18:, Folder 113)
    - Cover proof, undated (Box 18:, Folder 114)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 18:, Folder 115)
    - Reviews, 1987, 1990 (Box 18:, Folder 116)
  - Small poems again, 1986
    - Dummy, undated (Box 25:, Folder 182)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 25:, Folder 183)
    - Paste-up (photocopy), undated (Box 25:, Folder 184)
    - Reviews, 1986-1987 (Box 25:, Folder 185)
  - All the small poems, 1987
    - Cover art mockup, undated (Box 25:, Folder 186)
    - Cover art mockup, undated (Box 25:, Folder 187)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 25:, Folder 188)
    - Reviews, 1988 (Box 25:, Folder 189)
  - Nellie. A Cat on Her Own, 1989
    - Dummies (2), undated (Box 21:, Folder 137)
    - Preliminary sketches, undated (Box 21:, Folder 138)
    - Original art, undated
      - Jacket and title page (Box 21:, Folder 139)
      - Pp. 5-6 (Box 21:, Folder 140)
      - Pp. 7, 9 (Box 21:, Folder 141)
      - Pp. 11-12 (Box 21:, Folder 141)
      - Pp. 13-14 (Box 21:, Folder 143)
      - Pp. 17-18 (Box 21:, Folder 144)
      - Pp. 20, 22 (Box 21:, Folder 145)
      - Pp. 23, 25 (Box 21:, Folder 146)
      - Pp. 26-27 (Box 24:, Folder 147)
      - Pp. 29, 31 (Box 21:, Folder 148)
      - Unnumbered page (Box 21:, Folder 149)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 21:, Folder 150)
    - Jacket proofs, undated (Box 21:, Folder 150)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 21:, Folder 151)
    - Publicity and reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 21:, Folder 153)
  - Bub, or, the very best thing, 1994
    - Manuscript drafts, with annotations, undated (Box 29:, Folder 208)
    - Original sketches, undated (Box 31:, Folder 209)
    - Photocopied sketches, undated (Box 31:, Folder 210)
    - Original watercolor art--unused, undated (Box 31:, Folder 211)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 29:, Folder 212)
    - Photocopied dummy, undated (Box 31:, Folder 213)
    - Photocopied unused art, undated (Box 29:, Folder 214)
    - Dummy pages, copies, undated (Box 29:, Folder 215)
    - Binding sample, undated (Box 29:, Folder 216)
    - Stapled F+G in jacket mockup, undated (Box 29:, Folder 217)
    - Publicity and reviews, undated (Box 29:, Folder 218)
  - Elsie times eight, 2001
    - Story text with revisions, undated (Box 29:, Folder 219)
    - Sketches and watercolors--original and photocopies, undated (Box 31:, Folder 220)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 29:, Folder 221)
    - Cover art--used and unused, undated (Box 29:, Folder 222)
    - Jacket flap text, undated (Box 29:, Folder 223)
    - Binding sample, undated (Box 29:, Folder 224)
    - F+G with jacket mockup, undated; (2 items) (Box 29:, Folder 225)
    - Publicity and reviews, undated (Box 29:, Folder 226)
    - Publicity poster, undated (Box 31:, Folder 227)
  - Jack Plank Tells Tales, 2007
    - Edited manuscript drafts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 228)
    - Research photographs [on plain paper], undated (Box 30:, Folder 229)
    - Research photographs, undated (Box 28:, Folder 230)
    - Original sketches, undated (Box 31:, Folder 231)
    - Original art, pp. vi, x, 3, 5, 11, 15, 21, 23, 35, 44, undated (Box 30:, Folder 232)
    - Original art, pp.53, 57, 65, 71, 77, 83, 93, 97, 107, 113, 121, 129, undated (Box 31:, Folder 233)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 30:, Folder 234)
    - Binding sample, undated (Box 30:, Folder 235)